<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on We fight with cards - Weekly newsletter about Digital Card Games</title>
    <link>https://wefightwithcards.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on We fight with cards - Weekly newsletter about Digital Card Games</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2017 13:31:11 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://wefightwithcards.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Entropia on Kickstarter</title>
      <link>https://wefightwithcards.com/posts/entropia-new-card-game-kickstarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 04:48:45 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wefightwithcards.com/posts/entropia-new-card-game-kickstarter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;content is-clearfix&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;card sidebar inverse&#34;&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;card-image&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://wefightwithcards.com/images/entropia/logo.jpg&#34;&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
        &lt;div class=&#34;card-content&#34;&gt;
            &lt;ul class=&#34;menu-list&#34;&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;2-6 players&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Teams mode&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;54 cards with multiple choices&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Paper game&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Print&#39;n Play version&lt;/li&gt;
                &lt;li&gt;Kickstarter ends soon!&lt;/li&gt;
            &lt;/ul&gt;
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;p class=&#34;first&#34;&gt;
        In Entropia, a young star is born and chases its destiny among the suns and planets of the galaxy.
        Ending on Kickstarter this week, Entropia is a fresh card game with familiar mechanics and a friendly price.
    &lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&#34;box&#34;&gt;
        &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/627502834/entropia-the-card-game/&#34;&gt;Back Entropia&lt;/a&gt;
        for a print-n-play version, or get the Premium edition, delivered in a quality metal box.
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;
        &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-angle-double-down has-text-success&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;
        &lt;a href=&#34;#reveal&#34;&gt;Jump to the special card reveal!&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/p&gt;


    &lt;h2&gt;A star is born&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Each player is a young star that is trying to form their very own planetary system in which to reside.
        The first person to control five planers wins the round, and the first player to reach 3 rounds wins.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The game is rather small, at 54 cards total. But stategy is key mdash; as each card can be used in different ways:&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;you can keep the planet&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;or you can discard and choose an effect on play&lt;/li&gt;
     &lt;li&gt;and you can create combos&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Other players will try to steal or even destroy your planets, so you&#39;ll need to get creative fast. Different actions and ways to combo ensure play variety, but also enable one strategy or another.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&#34;box&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figure class=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://wefightwithcards.com/images/entropia/entropia1.jpg&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;h2&gt;Who should play?&lt;/h2&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I find it&#39;s a great intro to more serious card games, because it has familiar concepts from other popular card games like Hearthstone or Magic.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The cards allow you to draw &amp;amp; discard, build a board state or attack an opponent, do combos and tempo swings. (yes, we&#39;re card nerds here!)&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&#34;box&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figure class=&#34;image&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://wefightwithcards.com/images/entropia/combo.jpg&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;As you can see, you can have events like &#34;When you attract a planet&#34;, which you can manipulate with another card &amp;mdash; you&#39;ll be &lt;a href=&#34;http://gatherer.wizards.com/Pages/Card/Details.aspx?name=ponder&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;pondering&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; this play &lt;i class=&#34;fa fa-smile-o&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;h2&gt;Game modes&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;The game can be played with 2 to 6 players, although it&#39;s best when 4 people duke it out. There&#39;s also a &lt;b&gt;Teams&lt;/b&gt; mode with 2v2 or 2v2v2, each team with their own mechanics and team strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;What sounds really good for a game this size is the upcoming &lt;em&gt;Big Bad Boss Battle&lt;/em&gt; mode which pits 2-3 players against 1 powerful star. This is reminiscent of Magic&#39;s Archenemy format, which I&#39;ve always wanted to try, but never did it, since it requires special cards and rules.
        This game mode is still in testing and will be released as a free rule-book.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;a name=&#34;reveal&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;h2&gt;Special reveal&lt;/h2&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;We also have a surprise for existing and future backers! Two new cards have been revealed. The first one highlights the choice aspect, present on a lot of cards.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div class=&#34;box&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figure class=&#34;card&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://wefightwithcards.com/images/entropia/reveal.jpg&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;
        The second reveal is a little more cryptic! It&#39;s an unstable planet &amp;mdash; can&#39;t wait to find out what this does!
    &lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;box&#34;&gt;
        &lt;figure class=&#34;card&#34;&gt;
            &lt;img src=&#34;https://wefightwithcards.com/images/entropia/unstable.jpg&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;/figure&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Shadowverse Next shakes up the game</title>
      <link>https://wefightwithcards.com/posts/shadowverse-news-portalcraft-rotation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 04:48:45 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wefightwithcards.com/posts/shadowverse-news-portalcraft-rotation/</guid>
      <description>Shadowverse is a manga-style digital CCG available on mobile and Steam. The game took the world by storm, counting over 14 million downloads.
  Set Rotation! New class: Portalcraft All changes December 28 Plus a new set! In-game Tournaments in 2018    Big news this week for Shadowverse players: developer CyGames showcased their set of announcements, dubbed &#34;Shadowverse Next&#34;, which are bound to shake up the game in December.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MTG Arena Developer Q&amp;A</title>
      <link>https://wefightwithcards.com/posts/mtg-arena-developer-qa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 04:48:45 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wefightwithcards.com/posts/mtg-arena-developer-qa/</guid>
      <description>MTG: Arena is a new digital CCG in Wizard&#39;s Magic: the Gathering family. We&#39;re covering all the latest updates in our Arena series. Jump to: Cards - Beta info - Timeline - FAQs  Best of 1 Ladder in November Beta Best of 3 + sideboard is next Closed beta is Under NDA until 2018 PC Only for now Sign up for the Beta here    The MTG: Arena team held a Q&amp;amp;A session on Twitch about the upcoming beta.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MTG Arena beta timeline</title>
      <link>https://wefightwithcards.com/posts/mtg-arena-timeline/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 04:48:45 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wefightwithcards.com/posts/mtg-arena-timeline/</guid>
      <description>MTG: Arena is a new digital CCG in Wizard&#39;s Magic: the Gathering family. We&#39;re covering all the latest updates in our Arena series. Jump to: Cards - Beta info - Timeline - FAQs  Dev streams in October on Twitch Closed NDA beta starts in November Streaming allowed early 2018 PC Only for now Launches in 2018    The MTG: Arena team is gearing up for the Closed Beta with a series of streams in which they talk more about the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MTG: Arena Questions answered</title>
      <link>https://wefightwithcards.com/posts/mtg-arena-faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2017 04:48:45 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wefightwithcards.com/posts/mtg-arena-faq/</guid>
      <description>MTG: Arena is an upcoming free-to-play digital CCG in Wizard&#39;s Magic: the Gathering family.
  Closed beta starts in November All cards from Ixalan set All Standard sets at launch Focused on 1v1 battles PC Only for now Launches in 2018    Fun times ahead: MTG Arena starts closed beta soon, and this means we get more info about the game. Follow along as we try to answer all your questions about gameplay details, cards and sets, game types and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Magic the Gathering: Arena</title>
      <link>https://wefightwithcards.com/posts/mtg-arena-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Oct 2017 04:48:45 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wefightwithcards.com/posts/mtg-arena-intro/</guid>
      <description>MTG: Arena is a new digital CCG in Wizard&#39;s Magic: the Gathering family. Here&#39;s all the info we have on the launch, cards and sets, game types, FAQs and more. Jump to: Cards - Beta info - Timeline - FAQs  Closed beta starts in November PC Only for now Launches in 2018 All cards from Ixalan set All Standard sets at launch Focused on 1v1 battles    Hearthstone took the world by storm and gave new life to what seemed to be an established genre.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A guide to Elder Scrolls: Legends for Hearthstone players</title>
      <link>https://wefightwithcards.com/posts/elder-scrolls-legends-guide-hearthstone-players/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 23:48:45 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wefightwithcards.com/posts/elder-scrolls-legends-guide-hearthstone-players/</guid>
      <description>original article by /u/Karandor  Do you need a break from Hearthstone? Is the SmOrC too much? Does the Lich King put you off with his icy puns? Then look no further than The Elder Scrolls: Legends, the CCG set in the popular TES universe. The new Skyrim expansion is out and the skies are full of dragons, so there&#39;s no better time to join the fray!
This guide will get you started in no time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Frivolity</title>
      <link>https://wefightwithcards.com/posts/card-city-nights-ludosity-interview-multiplayer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2017 23:48:45 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://wefightwithcards.com/posts/card-city-nights-ludosity-interview-multiplayer/</guid>
      <description>If you’re a fan of card games, you probably heard of Card City Nights by now. Released back in 2014, the quirky card game was a mash-up featuring characters from Ludosity’s other games, reimagined as card players. With an interesting core mechanic, stellar soundtrack and spiffy characters, the game was well-received and still provides a refreshing experience 3 years later. So naturally, fans are eagerly awaiting the sequel! The upcoming Card City Nights 2 launches September 1 on Steam.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>